ADAM XIAO

(484)-319-9224 ● adam.x.xiao@gmail.com ● github.com/adam-xiao ● adamxiao.com

SUMMARY

Experienced in Full Stack Web Development with a background in biological sciences / engineering. Possess strong skills in team facilitation, customer relations, optimization and analogous problem solving that help companies approach projects in an holistic, organized fashion and address any problems from a wide scope.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby Rails Javascript React HTML CSS SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Horizons - Github

Travel Planning and Landmark Discovery Web App

- Designed with usability in mind, potential to facilitate client to travel agent interaction
- Connected with Google Places API to perform landmark discovery

Pantry Hero - Github

Recipe Finder - Parses User provided ingredients list to find makeable Recipes

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Hooked to the Tasty API to facilitate ingredient to recipe interaction

LetterBombs (Alphabet Game) - Github

A Speed / Reaction Browser Game

Created with Ruby on Rails backend and a Javascript frontend, utilized Javascript/CSS animations

EXPERIENCE

FUSION (Fostering Unity on Stage in One Night) - Multicultural Performances

 Collaborated with the university and various clubs to arrange and bring publicity to the event, while also recruiting performers for the showcase Lehigh University 04/2015

Holi (Hindu Spring Festival)

Contacted outside services in order to provide the necessary functions for the event

Lehigh University 11/2014

Steered the event so as to prevent safety risks and other unforeseen circumstances

Cognitive Science Department

Researcher

Lehigh University

09/2012 - 12/2012

Researched and compiled information on the effects of linguistic priming on response time

Asian Cultural Society (ACS)

VP of External Affairs and Event Committee,

Lehigh University Aug 08/2011-05/2015

- Fostered and maintained relationships with new and current club members
- Coordinated with other clubs to hold university-wide educational/social events in order to increase Lehigh's awareness of a diversifying nation

Peeps for a Purpose

Just Born Quality Confections 06/2010

Participant, Pennsylvania School for Global Entrepreneurship

- Devised a draft marketing plan for the introduction of Peeps into the UK.
- Plan revolved around a donation-based sponsorship from the RSPCA

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development/Software Engineering

Manhattan, NY 01/ 2020 - 05/2020

Lehigh University

Bethlehem, PA 08/2011 - 09/2016

Bachelor of Science in Bioengineering and Neuroscience

Woodberry Forest, VA

Woodberry Forest School

High Honors

09/2008 – 05/2011